# Daniel Kneipp

Artificial Intelligence Developer

#### Contact

119 Gloriosa st., Belo Horizonte, MG 305190-490, Brazil



+55 (31) 9-9605 3234 daniel.kneipp@ outlook.com



in://daniel-kneipp github://DanielKneipp gitlab://DanielKneipp

## Languages

Brazilian Portuguese [Mother tongue] English [Professional working proficiency]

# **Programming**

C++, Python, R, JavaScript, Matlab, Java, Bash

#### Skills

Machine Learning:



Optimization:



Text Mining: 

## About me

I am objective and focused on results. With entrepreneurship in my veins, I've spent many years studying and learning, from Convolutional Neural Networks to SWOT Analysis and Nash Equilibrium, trying to make a difference where I go. I know that it looks like a Miss Universe candidate speech asking for world peace (joke), but I really work hard to make some impact. Please, checkout my code repository (https://github.com/DanielKneipp) to see some cool stuff.

## **Education**

2016-2018 Master of Science

Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG)

Comptuer Science

My research area is DNA Computing. The objective is to propose functional chemical circuits for classification tasks using Chemical Reaction Networks theory as a programming language and DNA strands as the hardware. I'm a NanoComp lab. (http://www.nanocomp.dcc.ufmg.br/).

2012-2015 **Bachelor** of Science

Federal University of Viçosa (UFV)

Computer Science

I received Presidente Bernardes Medal for my academic excellence. Final Paper: A Genetic Algorithm for Multi-Component Optimization Problems: The Case of the Travelling Thief Problem.

2010-2011

Technician's Degree

SENAI School

Informatics

I Studied the basics of Computer Architecture, Software Development and Network Infrastructure.

#### **Independent** Courses

- Deep Learning Google | Udacity
- Machine Learning Stanford University | Coursera

# **Experience**

#### **Full time**

2017-Now Research and Development Analyst

MOST Specialist Technologies

Main activities:

- · Clustering and analysis of textual medical records;
- · Document classification based on its textual content;
- · Modular deployment of solutions using Docker.

#### Part time

2016-2017 Research Program

Invent Vision

Deep Learning research for Computer Vision applications. Implementation of a set of tools to speedup the development (including synthetic dataset generation) and deployment of image classifiers. Application deployment in embedded systems (NVIDIA Jetson). Project name: Smart monitoring system by georeferenced images for railways applications.

2015-2016 Trainee

Invent Visio

Research and implantation of distributed computing systems (based on Hadoop and Spark), developing simple applications made to run across clusters

2013-2014 Undergraduate Research

Invent Vision

Development of an efficient drowsiness detector based on face expressions (using face and eye tracking algorithms). Deployment made on x86 computers and ARM embedded systems. Project name: System for photometric inspection and automated adjustment of vehicle headlights. Project funded by CNPq (National Council for Scientific and Technological Development).

## **Awards**

2015 University Medal

Federal University of Viçosa

The *Presidente Bernardes* Medal is awarded to the students with academic excellence.

## **Communication skills**

2017 **Oral Presentation** 

**Evostar Conference** 

Presented the research I conducted to obtain my Bachelor's degree. It was about the usage of Genetic Algorithms to optimize and solve a multi-component combinatorial problem.

# **Publications**

# **Articles in journals**

A Comparison of Algorithms for Solving Multicomponent Optimization Problems

Daniel Kneipp Sa Vieira, Marcus Henrique Soares Mendes *IEEE Latin America Transactions 15.8 (2017) pp. 1474–1479. IEEE, 2017* 

# International conferences/proceedings

A Genetic Algorithm for Multi-component Optimization Problems: The Case of the Travelling Thief Problem

Daniel KS Vieira, Gustavo L Soares, Joao A Vasconcelos, Marcus HS Mendes European Conference on Evolutionary Computation in Combinatorial Optimization, 2017